<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<GenAiPromptTemplate xmlns="http://soap.sforce.com/2006/04/metadata">
    <activeVersionIdentifier>LeadConversionSummaryV1_1</activeVersionIdentifier>
    <description>AI prompt template for generating account summaries based on lead conversions</description>
    <developerName>Lead_Conversion_Summary</developerName>
    <masterLabel>Lead Conversion Summary</masterLabel>
    <templateVersions>
        <content>You are an expert marketing and sales analyst specializing in lead management and conversion optimization. You will analyze account data with a focus on leads and generate a comprehensive summary in English.

{!$Input:Account_Data}

Based on the account information provided above, generate a detailed analysis following this structure:

1. EXECUTIVE SUMMARY
Provide a 2-3 sentence high-level overview of the account's lead activity, conversion patterns, and growth potential from new business development.

2. KEY INSIGHTS
- Analyze lead conversion patterns and success rates
- Identify lead sources performing well for this account
- Assess lead quality and qualification effectiveness
- Evaluate time-to-conversion and velocity
- Highlight recent lead conversion activity and its significance

3. OPPORTUNITIES IDENTIFIED
- Additional marketing channels or campaigns to pursue
- Relationship expansion based on lead data
- Cross-functional collaboration opportunities
- Strategic lead generation recommendations
- Account penetration and growth strategies

4. RISK FACTORS
- Lead source concentration or over-reliance
- Conversion bottlenecks or challenges
- Lead quality concerns
- Resource allocation issues
- Competitive positioning weaknesses

5. ACTION RECOMMENDATIONS
- Prioritized actions for sales and marketing teams
- Lead nurturing strategies
- Follow-up activities for recent conversions
- Stakeholder engagement plans
- Timeline for critical next steps

IMPORTANT GUIDELINES:
- Generate this summary in English, regardless of source data language
- Focus on lead conversion effectiveness and growth potential
- Provide specific insights about lead sources and conversion patterns
- Connect lead activity to broader account strategy
- Use markdown formatting for better readability
- Target length: 400-600 words total
- Maintain a professional, analytical tone
- Base insights on the data provided, avoid speculation

Format your response with clear section headers and bullet points where appropriate.</content>
        <inputs>
            <apiName>Account_Data</apiName>
            <definition>primitive://String</definition>
            <masterLabel>Account_Data</masterLabel>
            <referenceName>Input:Account_Data</referenceName>
            <required>true</required>
        </inputs>
        <primaryModel>sfdc_ai__DefaultGPT5</primaryModel>
        <status>Published</status>
        <versionIdentifier>LeadConversionSummaryV1_1</versionIdentifier>
    </templateVersions>
    <type>einstein_gpt__flex</type>
    <visibility>Global</visibility>
</GenAiPromptTemplate>
